Herz, John H.; Papers ger015
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Essayistic writings, poetry, short prose, 1930-2005; 6; 305 file folders
  - Reviews by Herz of works by others, 6.161 (Box 12 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 110-130)
    - Otto Göppert.Der Völkerbund, 1939 (Box 13 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 12)
    - Werner Gramsch.Grundlagen und Methoden internationaler Revision, 1937 (Box 13 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 13)
    - Paul Guggenheim.Lehrbuch des Voelkerrechts, 1948 (Box 13 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 14)
    - Christian Hacke.Amerikanische Nahost-Politik - Kontinuität und Wandel von Nixon bis Reagan, 1985 (Box 13 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 15)
    - Lord Hailey.The Future of Colonial Peoples, 1944 (Box 13 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 16)
    - Karl Alfred Hall; Reinhard Höhn; Richard Busch; Karl-Heinz Bremer, 1934 (Box 13 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 17)
    - Wolfram F. Hanreider.The Stable Crisis - Two Decades of German Foreign Policy, 1971 (Box 13 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 18)
    - Arnold J. Heidenheimer.Adenauer and the CDU, 1961 (Box 13 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 19)
    - Wilhelm Hennis.Politik und praktische Philosophie, 1963 (Box 13 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 20)
    - Frederick Hertz.The Development of the German Public Mind; Leonard Krieger. The German Idea of Freedom, 1958 (Box 13 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 21)
    - Joe J. Heydecker / Johannes Leeb.The Nuremberg Trial, 1962 (Box 13 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 22)
    - Fritz Hippler.Staat und Gesellschaft bei Mill, Marx und Lagarde, 1935 (Box 13 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 23)
    - Reinhard Höhn.Die Wandlung im staatsrechtlichen Denken, 1935 (Box 13 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 24)
    - Reinhard Höhn / Theodor Maunz / Ernst Swoboda.Grundfragen der Rechtsauffassung, 1938 (Box 13 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 25)
    - Stanley H. Hoffmann.Contemporary Theory in International Relations, 1961 (Box 13 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 26)
    - Louise W. Holborn.Refugees: A Problem of Our Time, 1976 (Box 13 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 27)
    - Henrik Kaestlin.Die Anpassung des staatlichen Rechts an den Völkerbundspakt, den Kellogg-Pakt und den Vertrag von Versailles, 1936 (Box 13 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 28)
    - Friedrich Klein.Institutionelle Garantien und Rechtsinstitutsgarantien, 1935 (Box 13 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 29)
    - Walther Krüger.Das Gorgonenhaupt. Zukunftsvisionen der modernen bildenden Kunst, Musik, Literatur, 1973 (Box 13 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 30)
    - W. W. Kulski.International Politics in a Revolutionary Age, 1964 (Box 13 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 31)
    - Karl Larenz; Günther Korth, 1935 (Box 13 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 32)
    - Asche Graf von Mandelsloh.Politische Pakte und völkerrechtliche Ordnung, 1937 (Box 13 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 33)
    - Alfred von Martin.Die Religion Jacob Burckhardts, 1948 (Box 13 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 34)
    - Wolfgang J. Mommsen.Max Weber and German Politics 1890-1920, 1986 (Box 13 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 35)
    - Roger Morgan.The Study of International Affairs, 1972 (Box 13 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 36)
    - Fritz Münch.Die Bundesregierung, 1954 (Box 13 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 37)
    - William F. Obering.The Philosophy of Law of James Wilson, 1939 (Box 13 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 38)
    - Waldemar Paira.Das Zwangsgeld im preußischen Polizeiverwaltungsgesetz vom 1. Juni 1931..., 1935 (Box 13 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 39)
    - F. Parkinson.The Philosophy of International Relations, 1977 (Box 13 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 40)
    - Roscoe Pound.Contemporary Juristic Theory, Undated (Box 13 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 41)
    - Inge Rapoport.My Three Lives, 1999 (Box 13 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 42)
    - Hans Rathschlag.Die Bedeutung der Antinomien für den Kritizismus, 1936 (Box 13 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 43)
    - Cromwell A. Riches.Majority Rule in International Organization, 1942 (Box 13 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 44)
    - W. W. Rostow.The United States in the World Arena, 1960 (Box 13 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 45)
    - Wilfried Schaumann.Die Gleichheit der Staaten; Hans Wiebringhaus. Das Gesetz der funktionellen Verdoppelung, 1959 (Box 13 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 46)
    - Dietrich Schindler.Recht, Staat, Völkergemeinschaft, 1948 (Box 13 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 47)
    - Erich Schmidt-Leichner.Unrechtsbewußtsein und Irrtum in ihrer Bedeutung für den Vorsatz im Strafrecht, 1935 (Box 13 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 48)
    - Carl Schmitt.Völkerrechtliche Grossraumordnung mit Interventionsverbot für raumfremde Mächte, 1939 (Box 13 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 49)
    - Peter Schneider.Ausnahmezustand und Norm, 1957 (Box 13 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 50)
    - Adolf F. Schnitzer.Vergleichende Rechtslehre, 1947 (Box 13 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 51)
    - Wilhelm Schumacher. "Die vorläufige Entlassung (§§23-26 StGB)", 1934 (Box 13 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 52)
    - Mechthild Semper.Deutscher Bund und Völkerbund als Organisationen zur Friedenssicherung, 1936 (Box 13 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 53)
    - Société des Nations.Recueil des Accords intellectuels, 1938 (Box 13 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 54)
    - Alfons Steiniger.Das Blocksystem, 1950 (Box 13 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 55)
    - Carola Stern.Ulbricht: A Political Biography, 1965 (Box 13 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 56)
    - Fritz Stern.The Politics of Cultural Despair, 1962 (Box 13 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 57)
    - J.P. Stern.Hitler und die Deutschen, 1983 (Box 13 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 58)
    - Joachim Suche.Der Meerengenvertrag von Montreux vom 20. Juli 1936..., 1937 (Box 13 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 59)
    - Kenneth Thompson.Political Realism and the Crisis of World Politics, 1960 (Box 13 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 60)
    - Kenneth Thompson / Robert J. Myers.Truth and Tragedy, 1978 (Box 13 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 61)
    - Richard W. Tims.Germanizing Prussian Poland, 1942 (Box 13 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 62)
    - Arnold Toynbee.Study of History, Undated (Box 13 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 63)
    - Heinrich Triepel.Die Hegemonie: Ein Buch von führenden Staaten, 1939 (Box 13 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 64)
    - The True Facts about the Expropriation of the Oil Companies' Properties in Mexico, 1940 (Box 13 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 65)
    - Robert C. Williams.Culture in Exile. Russian Emigrés in Germany 1881-1941, 1973 (Box 13 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 66)
    - J. M. Yepes.Le panaméricanisme au point de vue historique, juridique et politique, 1937 (Box 13 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 67)
    - Gordon C. Zahn.German Catholics and Hitler's Wars, 1962 (Box 13 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 68)
- Texts of lectures, conference materials; course notes & lectures, 7; 133 file folders
  This series contains typescripts as well as some handwritten notes to lectures delivered by Herz at universities in the U.S. and Germany, as well as at conferences and seminars. In addition to Herz's lectures, this series also contains additional conference materials and papers delivered by others. Herz's teaching materials, including syllabi, reading lists, examination questions and lecture notes are also found in this series.
  - List of lectures delivered, Undated (Box 13 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 69)
  - Lecture announcements, programs, 1940s-1960s (Box 13 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 70)
  - Lecture announcements, programs, 1970s-1980s (Box 13 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 71)
  - "The Bases of National Socialist Creed", Undated (Box 13 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 72)
  - "Ethics and Foreign Policy", Undated (Box 13 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 73)
  - "German Ideas on Russo-German Relations between the Wars", Undated (Box 13 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 74)
  - Address at Trinity College, Hartford, CT, 1940 (Box 13 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 75)
  - "Senator McCarthy und die gegenwärtige Lage im amerikanischen Regierungssystem", 1953 (Box 13 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 76)
  - "Zum Begriff der politischen Freiheit". Radio talk, 1953 January 13 (Box 13 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 77)
  - American Political Science Association. 52nd Annual Meeting, Washington, D.C., 1963 September 06-1963 September 08 (Box 13 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 78)
  - Berkeley lectures, 1959 (Box 13 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 79)
  - "Political Aspects of the Armaments Issue", 1959 August 11 (Box 13 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 80)
  - "Lessons of the Cuban Crisis", ca. 1960 (Box 13 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 81)
  - "The Nation-State", ca. 1960 (Box 13 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 82)
  - "A Short History of War Expenditures - Or, the American Taxpayer Pays", ca. 1960 (Box 13 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 83)
  - Lecture at Smith College, Northampton, MA, ca. 1963 (Box 13 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 84)
  - "The Effect of Nuclear Weapons on International Politics", 1963 May 03 (Box 13 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 85)
  - "The Relevancy and Irrelevancy of Appeasement". APSA, 1963 September 04-1963 September 07 (Box 13 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 86)
  - "On Acceleration". Columbia University, ca. 1964 (Box 13 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 87)
  - Lecture at Connecticut and Amherst colleges, ca. 1964 (Box 13 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 88)
  - "Amerika" (Marburg, 1968) (Box 13 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 89)
  - "Vietnam - Exception or Pattern for Future U.S. Policy", ca. 1969 (Box 13 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 90)
  - "German Foreign Policy". APSA meeting, 1970 (Box 13 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 91)
  - "German Government and Politics from the Textbook Author's Viewpoint" (Bloomington, IN), 1972 March 24-1972 March 25 (Box 13 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 92)
  - "The Impact of Changing Patterns of International Relations on Divided Nations". International Symposium on Peace and Security in East Asia, Seoul, Korea, 1974 January 21-1974 January 24 (Box 13 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 93)
  - International Symposium on Peace and Security in East Asia, Seoul, Korea. Paper by Min Kwan-shik, Undated (Box 13 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 94)
  - International Symposium on Peace and Security in East Asia, Seoul, Korea. Paper by A. Bargmann, Undated (Box 13 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 95)
  - International Symposium on Peace and Security in East Asia, Seoul, Korea. Paper by Gisbert H. Flanz, Undated (Box 13 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 96)
  - International Symposium on Peace and Security in East Asia, Seoul, Korea. Paper by Albert Gorvine, Undated (Box 13 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 97)
  - International Symposium on Peace and Security in East Asia, Seoul, Korea. Paper by Sungjoo Han, Undated (Box 13 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 98)
  - International Symposium on Peace and Security in East Asia, Seoul, Korea. Paper by Arnold L. Horelick, Undated (Box 13 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 99)
  - International Symposium on Peace and Security in East Asia, Seoul, Korea. Paper by Yung-hwan Jo, Undated (Box 13 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 100)
  - International Symposium on Peace and Security in East Asia, Seoul, Korea. Paper by Ilpyong J. Kim, Undated (Box 13 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 101)
  - International Symposium on Peace and Security in East Asia, Seoul, Korea. Paper by Myung-sik Lee, Undated (Box 13 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 102)
  - International Symposium on Peace and Security in East Asia, Seoul, Korea. Paper by Masahide Kanayama, Undated (Box 13 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 103)
  - International Symposium on Peace and Security in East Asia, Seoul, Korea. Paper by James William Morley, Undated (Box 13 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 104)
  - International Symposium on Peace and Security in East Asia, Seoul, Korea. Paper by Ishwer C. Ojha, Undated (Box 13 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 105)
  - International Symposium on Peace and Security in East Asia, Seoul, Korea. Paper by Benjamin Rivlin, Undated (Box 13 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 106)
  - International Symposium on Peace and Security in East Asia, Seoul, Korea. Paper by Hiromi Teratani, Undated (Box 13 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 107)
  - International Symposium on Peace and Security in East Asia, Seoul, Korea. Paper by Nathaniel B. Thayer, Undated (Box 13 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 108)
  - International Symposium on Peace and Security in East Asia, Seoul, Korea. Paper by Donald Zagoria, Undated (Box 13 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 109)
  - "Détente in Historical Perspective". CUNY, 1974 October 25-1974 October 26 (Box 13 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 110)
  - "Technology, Ethics, and International Relations". Haifa, Israel, 1974 December 22-1974 December 25 (Box 13 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 111)
  - Haifa, Israel symposium papers, 1974 December 22-1974 December 25 (Box 13 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 112)
    Includes papers by: Judith Buber Agassi, Max Black, David G. Brandon, Mario Bunge, Broth Michael Dubois, René Dubos, Jacques Ellul, Robin Fox, Gilbert Herbert, Hans Jonas, Rollo May, Gotthold Müller, Franz Ollendorff, Anthony Peranio, Herbert Schnadelbach, Henri Schramek, Joseph Shepher, Leo Steg, Laurence H. Tribe.
  - Statement upon receipt of Order of Merit, 1975 April 10 (Box 13 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 113)
  - "Evolution of Western Societies. Divergent Patterns and Pace-Setting Solutions". Czempiel seminar, Frankfurt, ca. April 1975 (Box 13 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 114)
  - "Die Aula. Technik, Ethik und Internationale Beziehungen". Südwestfunk, 1975 December 21 (Box 13 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 115)
  - "The European Left Confronts Modernity". CUNY, 1976 April 26-1976 April 27 (Box 13 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 116)
    Also correspondence with Bernard E. Brown, 1976-1977.
  - "Power Politics or Ideology? The Nazi Experience", 1976 October 15-1976 October 16 (Box 13 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 117)
  - "Social Democracy vs. Democratic Socialism". CUNY conference, 1976 November 18-1976 November 20 (Box 13 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 118)
  - Ossip K. Flechtheim. "The German Left and the World Crisis". CUNY conference, 1976 November 18-1976 November 20 (Box 13 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 119)
  - Lecture in Czempiel seminar, Univ. Frankfurt, 1977 June 22 (Box 13 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 120)
  - Democracy lecture. Univ. of Massachusetts, Amherst, 1979 March (Box 13 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 121)
  - "Die ökologische Krise als Thema der Futurologie und der politischen Praxis", 1979 April 27-1979 April 28 (Box 13 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 122)
  - Edinger seminar lecture on German Foreign Policy. Columbia University, ca. 1980 (Box 13 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 123)
  - "Political Realism Revisited", 1980 March (Box 13 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 124)
  - "Successor Democracies". CUNY, 1980 November 20-1980 November 22 (Box 13 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 125)
  - "United States Foreign Policy at the Crossroads". CUNY, 1980 December 11-1980 December 12 (Box 13 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 126)
  - "Observations on the Recent German Bundestag Election". CUNY, 1980 December 17 (Box 13 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 127)
  - "Amerikanische Aussenpolitik im Wandel". Berlin, 1981 June 02 (Box 13 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 128)
  - "Role of the United States in International Relation". Königstein, 1981 June 18 (Box 14 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 1)
  - "Mit Reagan am Wendepunkt?" Südwestfunk, 1981 July 19 (Box 14 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 2)
  - "Teaching International Relations". Brooklyn College, CUNY, 1983 May 20 (Box 14 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 3)
  - "Reflections on Hans Morgenthau's Political Realism". CUNY, 1983 December (Box 14 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 4)
  - "In Honor of Ivo Duchacek", ca. 1984 (Box 14 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 5)
  - "Reflections on Gwendolen Carter's Approach to Political Science". APSA, 1984 September 01 (Box 14 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 6)
  - "Vom Überleben", 1984 September 26 (Box 14 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 7)
  - "Ansprache zum Empfang bei dem Oberbürgermeister der Stadt Düsseldorf (27.9.1984)", Undated (Box 14 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 8)
  - "The Responsibilites of a Political Scientist in an Age of Threatened Survival". Tenth annual CUNY Political Science Conference, 1984 December 07-1984 December 08 (Box 14 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 9)
  - "The Superpowers and Human Survival". CUNY, 1985 October 26 (Box 14 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 10)
  - "Otto Kirchheimer, Leben und Werk", 1985 November (Box 14 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 11)
  - The Center for European Studies.The Idea of Contemporary Europe, 1986 (Box 14 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 12)
  - "Israel's U.N. Membership in the Framework of the Postwar Power Struggle". Hebrew University, Jerusalem, Israel, 1986 July (Box 14 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 13)
  - "My Visit to Israel, June/July 1986", Undated (Box 14 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 14)
  - Hebrew University conference, Jerusalem, Israel. Paper by Abraham Bargman, 1986 July (Box 14 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 15)
  - Hebrew University conference, Jerusalem, Israel. Paper by Seymour Maxwell Finger, 1986 July (Box 14 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 16)
  - Hebrew University conference, Jerusalem, Israel. Paper by Nitza Nachmias, 1986 July (Box 14 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 17)
  - Hebrew University conference, Jerusalem, Israel. Paper by Benjamin Rivlin, 1986 July (Box 14 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 18)
  - Hebrew University conference, Jerusalem, Israel. Paper by Shlomo Slonim, 1986 July (Box 14 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 19)
  - Hebrew University conference, Jerusalem, Israel. Paper by Eliezer Yapou, 1986 July (Box 14 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 20)
  - "Open Societies - Closed Societies - No Societies". CUNY, 1986 December 11-1986 December 12 (Box 14 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 21)
  - "Entrance, Exist, and What To Do In-Between", ca. 1988 (Box 14 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 22)
  - "The Academy and Human Survival". Global Survival Symposium, 1988 March 28 (Box 14 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 23)
  - "State Crimes: Punishment or Pardon". Aspen Institute Conference, 1988 November 04-1988 November 06 (Box 14 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 24)
    Also papers by Margaret E. Crahan and Hugo Frühling; Jaime Malamud-Goti, José Zalaquett.
  - "Hans Morgenthau's Classical Realism in an Age of Endangered Human Survival". Munich, 1988 November (Box 14 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 25)
  - "Political Realism in an Age of Endangered Human Survival", 1989 February 24 (Box 14 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 26)
  - "Aussenpolitik im Zeitalter des bedrohten Menschheitsueberlebens", 1989 March 01 (Box 14 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 27)
  - "Weltpolitik als Erfahrung und als Interpretation", 1989 March (Box 14 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 28)
  - "Zur amerikanischen Aussenpolitik in der Aera Bush", 1989 November (Box 14 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 29)
  - "Implications of German Unification", 1990 April 25 (Box 14 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 30)
  - "Nuclear Weapons, Environmental Decay, and the Vitality of Nations". Harvard University, 1990 September 27 (Box 14 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 31)
    Also correspondence with Armand Clesse, 1990-1991.
  - "Looking at Carl Schmitt from the Vantage Point of the 1990s", 1990 October 29 (Box 14 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 32)
  - "The New Europe: Germany", 1991 April 26 (Box 14 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 33)
  - Düsseldorf conference, 1997 September 16 (Box 14 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 34)
  - International Relations Program, CUNY, 2000 December (Box 14 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 35)
  - "Remarks addressed to the participants in the session on the Security Dilemma at the International Studies Association conference, Portland, Oregon, February 2003", Undated (Box 14 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 36)
  - "Address to the Morgenthau Conference - Munich", 2004 October 28-2004 October 30 (Box 14 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 37)
  - Miscellaneous materials from lectures attended by Herz, 7.98 (Box 14 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 38-50)
    - Lecture announcements, CUNY, 1977-1994 (Box 14 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 38)
    - The Ralph Bunche Institute on the United Nations, lecture announcements, 1986-1993 (Box 14 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 39)
    - Programs of lectures & exhibits, 1977-1991 (Box 14 (7-Texts of lectures, conference materials; ), Folder 40)